KARLA FETTICH, PHD

I am enthusiastic about using my skills, expertise and 10+ years of healthcare analytics experience to make a lasting positive impact in the community. I lead teams to develop technical, analytics and ML/AI solutions, both professionally and through volunteer work. I have contributed to efforts to increase diversity in the Philadelphia data science community and provide analytics insights to nonprofit organizations in the greater Philadelphia area through datathons and software product development.

✓ kfettich at gmail dot com Language Download a PDF of this CV

SKILLS

ML/AI/STATS

Supervised Learning

Unsupervised Learning

Spark MLlib

LEADERSHIP

Vision & Strategy

TECHNICAL

SOL. NoSOL

Azure (Synapse, ML Studio)

SAS, SPSS

EDUCATION

Certifications

- · Managed Healthcare Professional (MHP) (AHIP; 2023)
- · Al Applications for Growth (Northwestern University; 2023)
- · Professional, Health Insurance Advanced Studies (PHIAS) (AHIP; 2021)

Formal Education

- · PhD, Psychology/Neuroscience (Temple University, 2011-2016)
- MA, Social Sciences/Psychology (The University of Chicago, 2008-2009)
- · BA, Psychology (Jacobs University Bremen, 2002-2005)



HEALTHCARE ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

present 2023

Lead Data Scientist

AmeriHealth Caritas

• Remote

• Remote

- · Technical lead for cloud migration to Databricks/Azure platforms,
- supporting DevOps/MLOps, data governance and change management • Design and manage the development of ML/Al products and solutions. incl. collaborating with stakeholders, process mapping, project planning,
- pre-deployment code review, and post-deployment validation · Drive innovation and data process quality improvements via ML feature
- stores, CI/CD, code review, and multidisciplinary event series for disseminating news and best practices company-wide
- · Improve code quality to achieve a run time speed reduction for a core company analytics product from 4h to 30m

2023 2021

Senior Data Scientist

AmeriHealth Caritas

· Developed ML models in R for risk stratification of LTSS members

- · Conducted exploratory data mining analyses, created insights decks and presentations to internal clients, and led a collaborative analytics project
- · Improved efficiency by reducing meeting overhead, automating workflows, developing solutions to transition from legacy systems, and coordinating with other teams to facilitate access tools
- · Led knowledge-sharing sessions on modern tools in data science

2021 2015

Head of Analytics & Algorithm Development

Orchestrall, Inc.

Phybrid (Conshohocken, PA)

- · Lead healthcare data science consulting projects to derive insights from clinical data and multidisciplinary teams
- · Develop and test predictive models for operational implementation
- · Select optimal tools for statistical modeling, including decision trees, logistic regression, conditional inference forests, multiple imputation
- · Develop algorithms to power intelligent healthcare applications for the senior care market, including outcome prediction, anomaly detection, and logistics optimization; our solution earned the Excellence in Technology Award for Dignity in Long-Term Care
- · Conduct end-to-end analyses including study design, data identification/collection, ETL, analysis, and communication of findings
- · Implement analytical models into production through collaborations with the software development team

2016 2013

Graduate Research Assistant

Neurocognition Lab

▼ Temple University

- · Introduced and applied machine learning techniques (e.g. support vector machines, multivoxel pattern analysis, graph theory, network analysis) and high performance computing tools
- · Assessed new data sources for value creation, attracting new research opportunities through a large, multi-site research network
- · Evaluated and communicated technical advantages and tradeoffs between statistical models

Prior experience

- · Graduate Clinical Research Assistant (Mechanisms of Affect Dysregulation Lab, Temple University; 2011-2013)
- · Graduate Teaching Assistant and Lab Instructor (Temple University; 2014)
- · Lead Clinical Research Coordinator (Adult Eating and Weight Disorders Clinic, The University of Chicago; 2009-2011)

I have 14 years of experience conducting academic research, including clinical trials and studies using neuroimaging and psychophysiological data.



present 2019

Project Leader

PAWS Data Pipeline

Philadelphia, PA

· Lead a team of volunteer developers to create a 360-degree view of PAWS' constituents and a data integration process from independent systems into SalesForce

2023 2018

Organizer & Board Member

R-Ladies Philadelphia

Philadelphia, PA

· Increased gender diversity in Philadelphia's data science community by creating learning, networking and leadership opportunities for over 1500 members via technical events and collaborations with other data groups I enjoy learning via hands-on projects that have a real and positive impact, and I seek to create opportunities to make this type of learning available to the wider community.

2020 2018

Lead Datathon Organizer

Collaborate with non-profit organizations to articulate business questions, translate them into viable analytics projects for volunteer data scientists; coordinate the volunteer effort, and help data scientists translate their findings into into clear and actionable business insights

Philadelphia, PA

- · Philadelphia Animal Welfare Society: Animal Shelter Volunteer Engagement (2018) and Animal Adoptions (2019)
- · Health Federation of Philadelphia, Prevention Point, the City of Philadelphia: Opioid Epidemic (2020)
- · Judge Accountability Table: Judicial patterns in Philadelphia courts (2021)

2022 2016

Dog Care Volunteer, Mentor

Philadelphia Animal Welfare Society (PAWS)

Philadelphia, PA



■ PAPERS & PUBLICATIONS

2019 2009 The interactive effects of peers and alcohol on functional brain connectivity in young adults (2019)

At risk of being risky: The relationship between "brain age" under emotional states and risk preference(2017)

Dissertation: Coordinated neuromorphology in the development of social information processing (2016)

Amygdala hyperactivation to angry faces in intermittent explosive dis - order (2016)

Emotion regulation deficits in intermittent explosive disorder(2014)

Loneliness mediates the relationship between emotion dysregulation and bulimia nervosa/binge eating disorder psychopathology in a clinical sample(2013)

Coping With Obesity Stigma Affects Depressed Mood in African-American and White Candidates for Bariatric Surgery(2012)

Correlates of Suicidal Ideation and/or Behavior in Bariatric-Surgery-Seeking Individuals With Severe Obesity(2012)

Factors Associated with Suicide Ideation in Severely Obese Bariatric Surgery-Seeking Individuals(2012)

MA Thesis: Predictors of Suicidality: Experiences of weight-related stigma in candidates for bariatric surgery(2009)

Made with the R package pagedown.

CV Source Code.

Last updated on 2024-05-03.